[
    {
        "id": "0",
        "question": "What two different ways can scientists can combine elements?",
        "options": [
            "a. Atoms or molecules.",
            "b. Atoms or compounds.",
            "c. Molecules or mixtures.",
            "d. Compounds or mixtures."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Compounds or mixtures."
    },
    {
        "id": "1",
        "question": " In which shell of an atom are the valence electrons located?",
        "options": [
            "a. The outermost.",
            "b. The middle.",
            "c. The second.",
            "d. The first."
        ],
        "correct": "a. The outermost."
    },
    {
        "id": "2",
        "question": "How would you best describes a positive ion?",
        "options": [
            "a. An atom that has an equal number of electrons and protons.",
            "b. An atom that lost an electron and has more protons.",
            "c. An atom that lost a proton and has more electrons.",
            "d. An atom that cannot throw off any protons."
        ],
        "correct": "b. An atom that lost an electron and has more protons."
    },
    {
        "id": "3",
        "question": "What material permits a large number of free electrons to move through it?",
        "options": [
            "a. Conductor.",
            "b. Insulator.",
            "c. Resistor.",
            "d. Ion."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Conductor."
    },
    {
        "id": "4",
        "question": "Which smallest current can be fatal under certain conditions?",
        "options": [
            "a. One-half of 1 amp",
            "b. One-third of 1 amp.",
            "c. One-tenth of 1 amp.",
            "d. One-eighth of 1 amp."
        ],
        "correct": "c. One-tenth of 1 amp."
    },
    {
        "id": "5",
        "question": "What is used to move a sufficient number of electrons to perform a useful job?",
        "options": [
            "a. Heat.",
            "b. Current.",
            "c. Voltage.",
            "d. Inductance."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Voltage."
    },
    {
        "id": "6",
        "question": "How is resistance defined with respect to electricity?",
        "options": [
            "a. The movement of electrons through a conductor.",
            "b. The opposition to voltage in an electrical circuit.",
            "c. The potential difference offered by a material.",
            "d. The opposition to current flow."
        ],
        "correct": "d. The opposition to current flow."
    },
    {
        "id": "7",
        "question": "According to Ohm's law, how much voltage is needed to push one ampere of current through one ohm of resistance?",
        "options": [
            "a. 0.1 volt.",
            "b. 1 volt.",
            "c. 10 volts.",
            "d. 100 volts."
        ],
        "correct": "b. 1 volt."
    },
    {
        "id": "8",
        "question": "What factor normally causes the resistance of a conductor to increase?",
        "options": [
            "a. Decrease in temperature.",
            "b. Increase in temperature.",
            "c. Decrease in length.",
            "d. Increase in size."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Increase in temperature."
    },
    {
        "id": "9",
        "question": "What unit of measurement is used to measure electrical power?",
        "options": [
            "a. Watts.",
            "b. Volts.",
            "c. Amps.",
            "d. Ohms."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Watts."
    },
    {
        "id": "10",
        "question": "How much power does a 3-horsepower motor consumes?",
        "options": [
            "a. 0.755 kilowatts (kW).",
            "b. 1.534 kW.",
            "c. 2.238 kW.",
            "d. 2.023 kW."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 2.238 kW."
    },
    {
        "id": "11",
        "question": "When do the magnetic lines of force in a magnet cross?",
        "options": [
            "a. When the north pole of a magnet is placed near the north pole of another magnet.",
            "b. When the south pole of a magnet is placed near the north pole of another magnet.",
            "c. When a permanent magnet and a temporary magnet are put together.",
            "d. Magnetic lines of force never cross each other."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Magnetic lines of force never cross each other."
    },
    {
        "id": "12",
        "question": "How can a polarity be created and the strength of the magnetic lines of force around a conductor be increased?",
        "options": [
            "a. By decreasing current.",
            "b. By increasing resistance.",
            "c. By looping coils close together.",
            "d. By increasing the size of the conductor."
        ],
        "correct": "c. By looping coils close together."
    },
    {
        "id": "13",
        "question": "What methods are the two most common for producing voltage?",
        "options": [
            "a. Chemical and mechanical.",
            "b. Magnetic and mechanical.",
            "c. Chemical and heat.",
            "d. Magnetic and heat."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Chemical and mechanical."
    },
    {
        "id": "14",
        "question": " What three things are needed to produce voltage by the principle of electromagnetic induction?",
        "options": [
            "a. Coil, core, and current.",
            "b. Magnet, housing, and prime mover.",
            "c. Coil, conductors, and relative motion.",
            "d. Magnetic field, a conductor, and relative motion."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Magnetic field, a conductor, and relative motion."
    },
    {
        "id": "15",
        "question": "What type of current flow is the result of voltages produced by batteries and thermocouples?",
        "options": [
            "a. Direct current.",
            "b. Alternating current.",
            "c. Easily transformed current.",
            "d. Current of no commercial value."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Direct current."
    },
    {
        "id": "16",
        "question": "Which formula is the correct one for finding the resistance of a circuit?",
        "options": [
            "a. Current divided by voltage.",
            "b. Voltage divided by current.",
            "c. Current divided by resistance.",
            "d. Voltage divided by resistance."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Voltage divided by current."
    },
    {
        "id": "17",
        "question": "How much resistance of a circuit is applied with voltage of 120 volts and a current flow of 9 amperes?",
        "options": [
            "a. 0.13 ohms.",
            "b. 1.3 ohms.",
            "c. 13.33 ohms.",
            "d. 108 ohms."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 13.33 ohms."
    },
    {
        "id": "18",
        "question": "What ohm measurement is the total resistance of a 5-ohm resistor and a 20-ohm resistor in parallel?",
        "options": [
            "a. 2 ohms.",
            "b. 2.5 ohms.",
            "c. 4 ohms.",
            "d. 5.5 ohms."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 4 ohms."
    },
    {
        "id": "19",
        "question": "What ohm measurement is the total resistance of a 4-ohm resistor, a 10-ohm resistor, and a 12-ohm resistor in parallel?",
        "options": [
            "a. 2.3 ohms.",
            "b. 3.2 ohms.",
            "c. 3.9 ohms.",
            "d. 4.2 ohms."
        ],
        "correct": "a. 2.3 ohms."
    },
    {
        "id": "20",
        "question": " What measurement is the current flow in amperes of a circuit with an applied voltage of 120 volts and a power consumption of 600 watts?",
        "options": [
            "a. 0.5 amperes.",
            "b. 2 amperes.",
            "c. 2.5 amperes.",
            "d. 5 amperes."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 5 amperes."
    },
    {
        "id": "21",
        "question": "What amount of power in watts is consumed by a circuit with 120 volts applied and a resistance of 12 ohms?",
        "options": [
            "a. 10 watts.",
            "b. 12 watts.",
            "c. 1200 watts.",
            "d. 1440 watts."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 1200 watts."
    },
    {
        "id": "22",
        "question": " How many watts of power are present in a 5-ohm unit of resistance in which 2 amperes are flowing?",
        "options": [
            "a. 20 watts.",
            "b. 15 watts.",
            "c. 10 watts.",
            "d. 2.5 watts."
        ],
        "correct": "a. 20 watts."
    },
    {
        "id": "23",
        "question": "What completes an electrical cycle of an alternating current (AC) generator?",
        "options": [
            "a. One positive and two negative alternations in one second.",
            "b. One positive and one negative alternation.",
            "c. One negative alternation.",
            "d. One positive alternation."
        ],
        "correct": "b. One positive and one negative alternation."
    },
    {
        "id": "24",
        "question": "How many rotations per minute (rpm) must a two-pole generator rotate to produce 60 hertz",
        "options": [
            "a. 1,200 rpm.",
            "b. 1,800 rpm.",
            "c. 3,600 rpm.",
            "d. 4,000 rpm."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 3,600 rpm."
    },
    {
        "id": "25",
        "question": "How is the measurement of the apparent power of an alternating current (AC) electrical system expressed?",
        "options": [
            "a. Volt-amperes.",
            "b. Kilovolt-amperes.",
            "c. Millivolt-amperes.",
            "d. Picovolt-amperes."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Kilovolt-amperes."
    },
    {
        "id": "26",
        "question": "What is the capacitance of a 125 microfarads (Î¼F) capacitor when converted to farads?",
        "options": [
            "a. .000125 F.",
            "b. .00125 F.",
            "c. .0125 F.",
            "d. 0.125 F."
        ],
        "correct": "a. .000125 F."
    },
    {
        "id": "27",
        "question": "The rules and equations for direct current (DC) circuits apply to alternating current (AC) circuits having",
        "options": [
            "a. resistive load elements alone.",
            "b. reactive load elements alone.",
            "c. capacitive load elements alone.",
            "d. resistive and reactive load elements."
        ],
        "correct": "a. resistive load elements alone."
    },
    {
        "id": "28",
        "question": "A 110-volt alternating current (AC) motor records 20 in-line amperes and the in-line wattmeter shows only 1,936 watts being consumed. What would be the power factor of the AC circuit?",
        "options": [
            "a. 80 percent power factor (pf).",
            "b. 83 percent pf.",
            "c. 86 percent pf.",
            "d. 88 percent pf."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 88 percent pf."
    },
    {
        "id": "29",
        "question": "What is the purpose of an electrical generator?",
        "options": [
            "a. Converts mechanical energy to electrical energy.",
            "b. Converts electrical energy to mechanical energy.",
            "c. Converts kinetic energy to electrical energy.",
            "d. Converts kinetic energy to potential energy."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Converts mechanical energy to electrical energy."
    },
    {
        "id": "30",
        "question": "What type of generator has brushes riding on the commutator to carry the current to an external circuit?",
        "options": [
            "a. Universal.",
            "b. Potential type.",
            "c. Direct current type.",
            "d. Alternating current type."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Direct current type."
    },
    {
        "id": "31",
        "question": "What feature is the advantage of having a rotating magnetic field alternator?",
        "options": [
            "a. It requires no slip rings and brushes.",
            "b. Output is taken from the commutator.",
            "c. Output is taken from the stationary stator coils.",
            "d. It requires less power to rotate the magnetic field."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Output is taken from the stationary stator coils."
    },
    {
        "id": "32",
        "question": "The voltage of a primary cell depends on the type of",
        "options": [
            "a. electrolyte and type of cell.",
            "b. cell and type of terminal posts.",
            "c. electrode material and type of cell.",
            "d. electrolyte and the electrode material."
        ],
        "correct": "d. electrolyte and the electrode material."
    },
    {
        "id": "33",
        "question": "Even though the open-circuit voltage of a lead-acid storage battery is approximately 2.2 volts, what number is the normal rating?",
        "options": [
            "a. 2.0.",
            "b. 2.5.",
            "c. 2.7.",
            "d. 2.9."
        ],
        "correct": "a. 2.0."
    },
    {
        "id": "34",
        "question": "A step-up transformer produces a secondary voltage",
        "options": [
            "a. higher and secondary current lower than the voltage and current in the primary. ",
            "b. lower and secondary current higher than the voltage and current in the primary.",
            "c. and current higher than the voltage and current in the primary.",
            "d. and current lower than the voltage and current in the primary."
        ],
        "correct": "a. higher and secondary current lower than the voltage and current in the primary."
    },
    {
        "id": "35",
        "question": "When setting up the bucket truck for rescue, where should you place the strap and how far from the bucket?",
        "options": [
            "a. Lower boom; 10 feet.",
            "b. Lower boom; 15 feet.",
            "c. Upper boom; 10 feet.",
            "d. Upper boom; 15 feet."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Upper boom; 10 feet."
    },
    {
        "id": "36",
        "question": "What two items do you need when setting up the bucket truck for rescue?",
        "options": [
            "a. Handline and a set of rope blocks.",
            "b. Strap and a set of rope blocks.",
            "c. Hot stick and handline.",
            "d. Strap and hot stick."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Strap and a set of rope blocks."
    },
    {
        "id": "37",
        "question": " Which piece of equipment should you use with the manhole guard when using the two-person method of manhole rescue?",
        "options": [
            "a. Handline.",
            "b. Wire hoist.",
            "c. Rope blocks.",
            "d. Windlass handcrank."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Windlass handcrank."
    },
    {
        "id": "38",
        "question": "When rescuing a person from a manhole, your primary concern should be",
        "options": [
            "a. your own safety.",
            "b. the speed of the rescue.",
            "c. the depth of the manhole.",
            "d. not to cause additional injuries."
        ],
        "correct": "a. your own safety."
    },
    {
        "id": "39",
        "question": "What action should you always take when using a two-way radio for line work?",
        "options": [
            "a. Get clearances from the shop",
            "b. Know where other crews are working.",
            "c. Identify yourself on each transmission.",
            "d. Use the electrical shop code on each transmission."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Identify yourself on each transmission."
    },
    {
        "id": "40",
        "question": "Who is responsible for issuing a safe clearance?",
        "options": [
            "a. Craftsman.",
            "b. Crew leader.",
            "c. Superintendent.",
            "d. Base civil engineer."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Superintendent."
    },
    {
        "id": "41",
        "question": "How many year(s) must safe clearance forms be retained after release?",
        "options": [
            "a. Four.",
            "b. Three.",
            "c. Two.",
            "d. One."
        ],
        "correct": "d. One."
    },
    {
        "id": "42",
        "question": "Which Air Force (AF) form is used to record all blocking and tagging actions done on primary electrical circuits on Air Force installations?",
        "options": [
            "a. AF Form 269, Electrical Facilities Safe Clearance.",
            "b. AF Form 561, BCE Weekly Work Schedule.",
            "c. AF Form 979, Danger Tag.",
            "d. AF Form 980, Caution Tag."
        ],
        "correct": "a. AF Form 269, Electrical Facilities Safe Clearance."
    },
    {
        "id": "43",
        "question": "Why do you use the Air Force (AF) Form 980, Caution Tag?",
        "options": [
            "a. To identify situations out of the ordinary.",
            "b. To control and record all blocking and tagging.",
            "c. To protect the crew working under safe clearance.",
            "d. To record the names of the crew that are doing the task."
        ],
        "correct": "a. To identify situations out of the ordinary."
    },
    {
        "id": "44",
        "question": "At which of the following voltages can you work from the structure using rubber gloves?",
        "options": [
            "a. 24,900 volts and below.",
            "b. 13,800 volts and below.",
            "c. 13,200 volts and below.",
            "d. 4,160 volts and below."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 4,160 volts and below."
    },
    {
        "id": "45",
        "question": "Which safety briefing point is not covered during a tailgate meeting? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Special practices or grounding requirements.",
            "b. Certification of live line maintenance.",
            "c. Description of the work to be done.",
            "d. Identification of the work site."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Certification of live line maintenance."
    },
    {
        "id": "46",
        "question": "What document is used to record system problems, such as outages, surges, or low voltages?",
        "options": [
            "a. Power outage log.",
            "b. Special procedure log.",
            "c. Emergency maintenance record",
            "d. Emergency operations checklist."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Power outage log."
    },
    {
        "id": "47",
        "question": " What records are kept to make sure proper maintenance and repair are done on the electrical distribution system?",
        "options": [
            "a. Equipment records only.",
            "b. Maintenance records only.",
            "c. Equipment and maintenance records.",
            "d. Equipment, maintenance, and computer data records."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Equipment and maintenance records."
    },
    {
        "id": "48",
        "question": "Which of the following is not required to establish a proper maintenance program?",
        "options": [
            "a. Knowing the scope of work.",
            "b. Establishing methods of application.",
            "c. Establishing intervals of performance.",
            "d. Having adequate and dependable supply of power."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Having adequate and dependable supply of power."
    },
    {
        "id": "49",
        "question": "Which instrument gives immediate qualitative information on the degree and type of distortion?",
        "options": [
            "a. Oscilloscope.",
            "b. Wave analyzer.",
            "c. Frequency meter.",
            "d. Spectrum analyzer."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Oscilloscope."
    },
    {
        "id": "50",
        "question": " What frequencies, in hertz (Hz), are the most common for transmission of electrical power?",
        "options": [
            "a. 50, 60, 5.",
            "b. 25, 50, 60.",
            "c. 25, 50, 400.",
            "d. 50, 60, 400."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 50, 60, 400."
    },
    {
        "id": "51",
        "question": "The output voltage of the electronic voltage regulator circuit",
        "options": [
            "a. cannot be adjusted to a specific value.",
            "b. can be adjusted to a specific value.",
            "c. is adjusted by the manufacturer.",
            "d. is adjusted automatically."
        ],
        "correct": "b. can be adjusted to a specific value."
    },
    {
        "id": "52",
        "question": "What purpose does the zener diode in the electronic voltage regulator serve?",
        "options": [
            "a. Acts as a biasing source.",
            "b. Regulates output voltage.",
            "c. Sets the reference voltage.",
            "d. Provides transistor reverse bias."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Sets the reference voltage."
    },
    {
        "id": "53",
        "question": "Input resistance to a common collector amplifier is high because the emitter signal opposes the",
        "options": [
            "a. base signal.",
            "b. base resistance.",
            "c. collector signal.",
            "d. output resistance."
        ],
        "correct": "a. base signal."
    },
    {
        "id": "54",
        "question": "The process of returning a part of the output of an amplifier back to its input in such a manner that it cancels part of the input signal is known as",
        "options": [
            "a. degeneration.",
            "b. signal cancellation.",
            "c. high-input impedance.",
            "d. regenerative feedback."
        ],
        "correct": "a. degeneration."
    },
    {
        "id": "55",
        "question": "Which gain characteristics of a common base transistor amplifier is less than one?",
        "options": [
            "a. Impedance.",
            "b. Voltage.",
            "c. Current.",
            "d. Power."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Current."
    },
    {
        "id": "56",
        "question": "The controlling element in a common base configuration is the",
        "options": [
            "a. emitter.",
            "b. collector.",
            "c. emitter base.",
            "d. collector base."
        ],
        "correct": "a. emitter."
    },
    {
        "id": "57",
        "question": " What does the positive alternation of an input signal to the base of an NPN transistor in a common emitter configuration cause?",
        "options": [
            "a. An increase in collector current.",
            "b. A decrease in collector current.",
            "c. An increase in base current.",
            "d. A decrease in base current."
        ],
        "correct": "c. An increase in base current."
    },
    {
        "id": "58",
        "question": "In the common emitter configuration, the input is between the emitter and base and the output is between the",
        "options": [
            "a. base and collector.",
            "b. base and common.",
            "c. emitter and common.",
            "d. collector and emitter."
        ],
        "correct": "d. collector and emitter."
    },
    {
        "id": "59",
        "question": "What does the word electronics mean?",
        "options": [
            "a. Vacuum.",
            "b. Optimum current flow.",
            "c. Precise voltage regulation.",
            "d. Applications involving the control of electricity."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Applications involving the control of electricity."
    },
    {
        "id": "60",
        "question": "An electron is considered a free electron when it reaches the",
        "options": [
            "a. nucleus.",
            "b. valence band.",
            "c. forbidden level.",
            "d. conduction band."
        ],
        "correct": "d. conduction band."
    },
    {
        "id": "61",
        "question": "A positive mobile charge is considered",
        "options": [
            "a. hole.",
            "b. valence.",
            "c. nucleus.",
            "d. rectifier."
        ],
        "correct": "a. hole."
    },
    {
        "id": "62",
        "question": "Excessive external heat applied to electronic components",
        "options": [
            "a. has no adverse effects.",
            "b. causes increased current flow.",
            "c. causes decreased current flow.",
            "d. improves operation of components."
        ],
        "correct": "b. causes increased current flow."
    },
    {
        "id": "63",
        "question": "Which device should only be used in direct current (DC) circuits?",
        "options": [
            "a. Electrolytic capacitors.",
            "b. Capacitors.",
            "c. Resistors.",
            "d. Diodes."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Electrolytic capacitors."
    },
    {
        "id": "64",
        "question": "Which of the following is another term for a diode? ",
        "options": [
            "a. PN junction.",
            "b. PN resistor.",
            "c. Amplifier.",
            "d. Triac."
        ],
        "correct": "a. PN junction."
    },
    {
        "id": "65",
        "question": " Which multimeter lead connection is used to read forward bias on a diode?",
        "options": [
            "a. Polarity does not matter.",
            "b. Black to cathode.",
            "c. Black to anode.",
            "d. Red to cathode."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Black to cathode."
    },
    {
        "id": "66",
        "question": "What does the arrow in semiconductors indicate?",
        "options": [
            "a. The direction of minority current receivers.",
            "b. The direction of majority current carriers.",
            "c. The direction of electron flow.",
            "d. The direction of hole current."
        ],
        "correct": "d. The direction of hole current."
    },
    {
        "id": "67",
        "question": "What does a flat side or shorter lead on some light emitting diodes indicate?",
        "options": [
            "a. Low voltage side.",
            "b. Anode.",
            "c. Junction.",
            "d. Cathode."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Cathode."
    },
    {
        "id": "68",
        "question": "What is a zener diode typically used for?",
        "options": [
            "a. Current negation.",
            "b. Current oscillation.",
            "c. Voltage regulation.",
            "d. Voltage amplification."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Voltage regulation."
    },
    {
        "id": "69",
        "question": "How are the electrode leads identified and labeled on a Bipolar Junction Transistor?",
        "options": [
            "a. Positive and negative.",
            "b. Anode and cathode.",
            "c. Emitter, base, and collector.",
            "d. Anode, cathode, and gate."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Emitter, base, and collector."
    },
    {
        "id": "70",
        "question": "Which letter combinations are types of Bipolar Junction Transistors?",
        "options": [
            "a. PNPN, NPNP.",
            "b. NNPP, PPNN.",
            "c. PNN, NPP.",
            "d. NPN, PNP."
        ],
        "correct": "d. NPN, PNP."
    },
    {
        "id": "71",
        "question": "How many layers of semiconducting material does a silicon controlled rectifier (SCR) have?",
        "options": [
            "a. Two.",
            "b. Three.",
            "c. Four.",
            "d. Five."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Four."
    },
    {
        "id": "72",
        "question": "How is the emitter base junction on a transistor connected?",
        "options": [
            "a. Forward biased.",
            "b. Reverse biased.",
            "c. Front biased.",
            "d. Rear biased."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Forward biased."
    },
    {
        "id": "73",
        "question": "How does the base of a transistor normally receive its control voltage?",
        "options": [
            "a. Multiplexor circuit.",
            "b. Voltage divider circuit.",
            "c. Independent battery circuit.",
            "d. Separately derived power source."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Voltage divider circuit."
    },
    {
        "id": "74",
        "question": "Transistors can be connected in how many configurations?",
        "options": [
            "a. Two.",
            "b. Three.",
            "c. Four.",
            "d. Six."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Three."
    },
    {
        "id": "75",
        "question": "What controls the conduction time of a silicon controlled rectifier (SCR)?",
        "options": [
            "a. A decrease in forward bias.",
            "b. A decrease in reverse bias.",
            "c. Anode current.",
            "d. Gate current."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Gate current."
    },
    {
        "id": "76",
        "question": "How do you turn off a silicon controlled rectifier (SCR) in a minimum amount of time?",
        "options": [
            "a. Apply reverse bias to the gate.",
            "b. Apply forward bias to the gate.",
            "c. Apply reverse bias to the anode.",
            "d. Apply forward bias to the anode."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Apply reverse bias to the anode."
    },
    {
        "id": "77",
        "question": "Information showing the location of installed distribution equipment should be kept",
        "options": [
            "a. on the maintenance truck.",
            "b. on a distribution map in the shop.",
            "c. in the distribution substation house.",
            "d. in the base civil engineer's (BCE) office."
        ],
        "correct": "b. on a distribution map in the shop."
    },
    {
        "id": "78",
        "question": "What is developed for logic gate circuits to determine signal output?",
        "options": [
            "a. Truth tables.",
            "b. Sizing charts.",
            "c. Component values.",
            "d. Operating thresholds."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Truth tables."
    },
    {
        "id": "79",
        "question": "Which of the following is not a logic gate?",
        "options": [
            "a. NAND.",
            "b. STOP.",
            "c. NOR.",
            "d. OR."
        ],
        "correct": "b. STOP."
    },
    {
        "id": "80",
        "question": "The two purposes of the load resistor of a half-wave rectifier is to develop the output signal and to",
        "options": [
            "a. provide reverse bias.",
            "b. determine output amplitude.",
            "c. limit current flow to a safe level.",
            "d. limit output voltage to a safe level."
        ],
        "correct": "c. limit current flow to a safe level."
    },
    {
        "id": "81",
        "question": "If the input frequency to a half-wave rectifier is 120 Hz, its output ripple frequency is",
        "options": [
            "a. 120 hertz (Hz).",
            "b. 240 Hz.",
            "c. 60 pulses per second (pps).",
            "d. 120 pps."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 120 pps."
    },
    {
        "id": "82",
        "question": "A full-wave rectifier can be identified easily on a schematic because it contains",
        "options": [
            "a. three diodes.",
            "b. a center-tapped transformer.",
            "c. two diodes with a cross resistor.",
            "d. a side transformer and four diodes."
        ],
        "correct": "b. a center-tapped transformer."
    },
    {
        "id": "83",
        "question": "The breakdown rating for diodes in a full-wave rectifier must be twice as great as the",
        "options": [
            "a. breakdown rating of one diode.",
            "b. half-wave rectifier diode.",
            "c. average output voltage.",
            "d. size of the load."
        ],
        "correct": "b. half-wave rectifier diode."
    },
    {
        "id": "84",
        "question": "What frequency is the output ripple of a bridge rectifier with an input frequency of 60 hertz (Hz)?",
        "options": [
            "a. 60 Hz.",
            "b. 60 pulses per second (pps).",
            "c. 120 pps.",
            "d. 120 Hz."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 120 pps."
    },
    {
        "id": "85",
        "question": "The output ripple frequency of a three-phase bridge rectifier is how many times the input frequency?",
        "options": [
            "a. Three times.",
            "b. Four times.",
            "c. Five times.",
            "d. Six times."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Six times."
    },
    {
        "id": "86",
        "question": "During pole-top rescue, the rope should be ",
        "options": [
            "a. tied through the back of the victim's body belt.",
            "b. tied through the front of the victim's body belt.",
            "c. passed through the crossarm braces and over the crossarm.",
            "d. passed around the victim's chest and tied with three half hitches."
        ],
        "correct": "d. passed around the victim's chest and tied with three half hitches."
    },
    {
        "id": "87",
        "question": "When testing the oxygen level of a confined space, the oxygen level should be within what percentage (%)?",
        "options": [
            "a. 18-20.",
            "b. 15-22.",
            "c. 19.5-23.5",
            "d. 18.5-22.5."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 19.5-23.5"
    },
    {
        "id": "88",
        "question": "Why does a ripple voltage exist in a circuit powered by a rectifier? ",
        "options": [
            "a. The rectifier supplies energy to the load in pulses.",
            "b. A characteristic of the rectifier is to store energy.",
            "c. Rectifiers supply a smooth voltage to the load.",
            "d. It is a characteristic of alternating current."
        ],
        "correct": "a. The rectifier supplies energy to the load in pulses."
    },
    {
        "id": "89",
        "question": "The bowline knot is placed in front of a victim in the two-person method of manhole rescue to",
        "options": [
            "The bowline knot is placed in front of a victim in the two-person method of manhole rescue to",
            "b. prevent the knot from slipping.",
            "c. prevent the victim's head from hitting the side of the manhole.",
            "d. allow the victim's head to tilt back, keeping the victim's air passage open."
        ],
        "correct": "d. allow the victim's head to tilt back, keeping the victim's air passage open."
    },
    {
        "id": "90",
        "question": "An inductive (choke) input filter gives a lower output voltage than the capacitive input LC filter and also",
        "options": [
            "a. inductive regulation.",
            "b. high-output impedance.",
            "c. poor voltage regulation.",
            "d. better voltage regulation."
        ],
        "correct": "d. better voltage regulation."
    },
    {
        "id": "91",
        "question": "Which of these characteristics are one of the pi-type LC filter?",
        "options": [
            "a. Low-input voltage and no voltage regulation.",
            "b. High-input voltage and no voltage regulation.",
            "c. Low-output voltage and better voltage regulation.",
            "d. High-output voltage and better voltage regulation."
        ],
        "correct": "d. High-output voltage and better voltage regulation."
    },
    {
        "id": "92",
        "question": "Which condition exists when you connect the negative battery lead to a cathode?",
        "options": [
            "a. Frontal bias.",
            "b. Neutral bias.",
            "c. Reverse bias.",
            "d. Forward bias."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Forward bias."
    },
    {
        "id": "93",
        "question": "The output of a three-phase bridge rectifier is of low amplitude and requires",
        "options": [
            "a. very little filtering.",
            "b. to be stepped up.",
            "c. heavy filtering.",
            "d. no filtering."
        ],
        "correct": "a. very little filtering."
    },
    {
        "id": "94",
        "question": "What type of current flow cannot be transformed from a higher voltage to a lower voltage?",
        "options": [
            "a. Alternating current.",
            "b. Direct current.",
            "c. Low current.",
            "d. Electric."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Direct current."
    },
    {
        "id": "95",
        "question": "How much current flow is in a circuit with 24 volts applied and with 72-ohms resistance?",
        "options": [
            "a. 0.33 amperes.",
            "b. 3.3 amperes.",
            "c. 33.0 amperes.",
            "d. 0.728 amperes."
        ],
        "correct": "a. 0.33 amperes."
    }
]